boom boom
Hey, everybody. How's it going? In this video, we're going to be learning about Python decorators.
We're going to be learning how decorators work,
and also when you would want to use them.
Ah, so, decorators are a slightly more advanced topic,
but we're going to walk through a few different
examples so that we can understand exactly what's going on.
Now, if you haven't watched my
videos on closures or first-class functions,
then you should probably give those videos a watch,
because they will explain a lot of the underlying concepts that I'm not going to spend a lot of time on here.
And I'll put a link to those videos in the comments section below.
But if you haven't seen those videos,
then let me just give a really quick summary.
Ah, so, first-class functions.
First-class functions allow us to
treat functions like any other object.
So, for example,
we can pass functions as arguments
to another function.
We can return functions.
And we can assign functions to variables.
Now, closures allow us to take advantage of first-class functions,
and return an inner function
that remembers and has access to
variables local to the scope in which they were created.
Now, if both of those definitions sound a little confusing,
then let's go ahead and take a look at a quick example here.
And again, I'm not going to go as in-depth
as I do in those
videos.
Ah, but let's just do a quick recap.
So, we have an outer function here that doesn't take any parameters.
And within our outer function,
we have a local variable called "message".
Ah, then we are creating an inner function
within the outer function.
Now, the "message" variable
wasn't created within the inner function,
but the inner function does
have access to it,
and this is what we call a free variable.
Now, all our inner function does
is print this message.
Then we are executing our inner function
and returning the result.
So now, if I execute this
outer function, here, and run this code,
what it does, is it comes in here
to this outer function,
sets this message variable,
ah, creates this inner function
so we can see any outer function is
we can do that by taking
So now we